RG 004:051, Fairfield Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Fairfield Probate Court records
1648-1911
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Fairfield District)
35.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1648-1755; Probate files, 1649-1911.
RG004_051
1929-003 and 1929-004
Historical Note
Fairfield, Fairfield County, Town established 1639
The Fairfield Probate District was constituted May 1666 session, as a County Court. The Fairfield Probate District serves the municipality of Fairfield. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Danbury, October 1687 - May 1744; Greenwich, May 1666 - May 1728; New Canaan, May 1801 - May 1802; New Fairfield, May 1740 - May 1744; Newtown, October 1711 - May 1744; Norwalk, May 1666 - May 1802; Redding, May 1767 - January 1782; Ridgefield, October 1709 - May 1728; Stamford, May 1666 - May 1728; Stratford, May 1666 - May 1782; Weston, October 1787 - May 21, 1832; Woodbury, 1698 - October 1719.
Town of Fairfield, Probate District chronology:
1639 - circa 1648, Hartford Colonial Jurisdiction
Circa 1648 - May 1666, Fairfield Particular Court
May 1666 - Present, Fairfield County Court & District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Record books, Volumes 1-10, 1648-1755. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 10. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1649-1911. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 10.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1929-003 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Danbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Fairfield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Greenwich; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Canaan; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Fairfield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Newtown; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Norwalk; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Redding; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Ridgefield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stamford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stratford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Weston; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Woodbury
Places:
Danbury (Conn.); Fairfield (Conn.); Greenwich (Conn.); New Canaan (Conn.); New Fairfield (Conn.); Newtown (Conn.); Norwalk (Conn.); Redding (Conn.); Ridgefield (Conn.); Stamford (Conn.); Stratford (Conn.); Weston (Conn.); Woodbury (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-39, 41-42, 44-45, 48-50, 52-53, 55-56, 58-63, 1648-1916; probate files, 1648-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1929-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 9, 1929 (1649-1911); March 27, 1936 (1693-1838). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 1929-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 9, 1929.
Container List
- Record books, 1648-1755; 2.5 cubic feet (10 volumes); 1929-003
  Previously catalogued as 345.42 fC753f
  - Records, 1648-1664 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1664-1675 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1676-1690 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1690-1702 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1702-1750 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1717-1735 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1721-1750 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1725-1740 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1741-1748 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1748-1755 (Volume 10)
- Probate files, 1649-1911; 33 cubic feet; 1929-003
  - Abbot - Alexander (Drawer 1)
  - Allen - Alvord, J. (Drawer 2)
  - Alvord, K. - Arnold, E. (Drawer 3)
  - Arnold, F. - Banks, B. (Drawer 4)
  - Arnold, F. - Banks, B. (Drawer 5)
  - Banks, Joseph - Banks. T. (Drawer 6)
  - Banks, U. - Beach, B. (Drawer 7)
  - Banks, U. - Beach, B. (Drawer 8)
  - Beardslee, J. - Beers, I. (Drawer 9)
  - Beers, J. - Benedict, D. (Drawer 10)
  - Benedict, E. - Bennett, K. (Drawer 11)
  - Bennett, L. - Betts, J. (Drawer 12)
  - Betts, K. - Birdseye (Drawer 13)
  - Bisbom - Booth, N. (Drawer 14)
  - Booth, O. - Bradley, D. (Drawer 15)
  - Bradley, E. - Bradley, L. (Drawer 16)
  - Bradley, M. - Brewster (Drawer 17)
  - Briggs - Brush (Drawer 18)
  - Bryant - Bulkley, I. (Drawer 19)
  - Bulkley, J. - Burnitt (Drawer 20)
  - Burr, A. - Burr, D. (Drawer 21)
  - Burr, E. - Burr, I. (Drawer 22)
  - Burr, J. - Burr, N. (Drawer 23)
  - Burr, O. - Burr, Z. (Drawer 24)
  - Burrall - Cable, E. (Drawer 25)
  - Cable, F. - Capers (Drawer 26)
  - Cardwell - Clark, S. (Drawer 27)
  - Clark, T. - Collyer (Drawer 28)
  - Colwell - Couch (Drawer 29)
  - Cowel - Curtis, I. (Drawer 30)
  - Curtis, J. - DeForest, C. (Drawer 31)
  - DeForest, D. - Dimon, I. (Drawer 32)
  - Dimon, J. -Downs, R. (Drawer 33)
  - Downs, S. - English (Drawer 34)
  - Everitt - Fairweather (Drawer 35)
  - Fanton - Fitch, E. (Drawer 36)
  - Fitch, F. - Frost, D. (Drawer 37)
  - Frost, E. - Godfrey, I. (Drawer 38)
  - Godfrey, J. - Gold, A. (Drawer 39)
  - Gold, B. - Gratis (Drawer 40)
  - Gray - Gregory, A. (Drawer 41)
  - Gregory, B. - Hale (Drawer 42)
  - Hall - Hanford, D. (Drawer 43)
  - Hanford, E. - Hawley, D. (Drawer 44)
  - Hawley, E. - Haynes, S. (Drawer 45)
  - Haynes, T. - Hide (Drawer 46)
  - Higgins - Hill (Drawer 47)
  - Hillyer - Holmes, D. (Drawer 48)
  - Holmes, E. - Hoyt (Drawer 49)
  - Hubbard - Hubbell, M. (Drawer 50)
  - Hubbell, N. - Hull, J. (Drawer 51)
  - Hull, K. - Hurlbutt, J (Drawer 52)
  - Hurlbutt, K. - Jeanes (Drawer 53)
  - Jennings, A. - Jennings, G. (Drawer 54)
  - Jennings, H. - Jennings, M. (Drawer 55)
  - Jennings, N. - Johnson, M. (Drawer 56)
  - Johnson, N. - Judson, M. (Drawer 57)
  - Judson, N. - Kellogg (Drawer 58)
  - Kennedy - Knapp, S. (Drawer 59)
  - Knapp, T. - Leathers (Drawer 60)
  - Leavensworth - Lewis (Drawer 61)
  - Lines - Lockwood, J. (Drawer 62)
  - Lockwood, K. - Lyon, A. (Drawer 63)
  - Lyon, B. - Lyon, T. (Drawer 64)
  - Lyon, U. - Mallory, B. (Drawer 65)
  - Mallory, C. - Mead, J. (Drawer 66)
  - Mead, K. - Meeker, M. (Drawer 67)
  - Meeker, N. - Middlebrooks, E. (Drawer 68)
  - Middlebrooks, F. - Moore (Drawer 69)
  - Morehouse, A. - Morehouse, Jesse (Drawer 70)
  - Morehouse, John - Morehouse, T. (Drawer 71)
  - Morehouse, U. - Newman (Drawer 72)
  - Nichols, A. - Nichols, H. (Drawer 73)
  - Nichols, I. - Nichols, Z. (Drawer 74)
  - Nickleson - Ogden, L. (Drawer 75)
  - Ogden, M. - Osborn, A. (Drawer 76)
  - Osborn, B. - Osborn, J. (Drawer 77)
  - Osborn, L. - Raymond, B. (Drawer 78)
  - Raymond, C. - Sanford, B. (Drawer 79)
  - Sanford, C. - Sherwood, C. (Drawer 80)
  - Sherwood, D. - Squire, A. (Drawer 81)
  - Squire, B. - Thompson (Drawer 82)
  - Osborn, B. - Wakeman, J. (Drawer 83)
  - Wakeman, K. - Whitehead, J. (Drawer 84)
  - Whitehead, K. - Zimmerman; Miscellaneous (Drawer 85)
- Inventory Control Book, 1649-1911; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1929-003
  Also known as the Godard Digest